这是盲目的本能反应!
It's blind instinct!
但现在奎迪回来了
But now it is Creed comin'back.
奎迪击出了左拳  是什么使这两个人撑下去的?
Creed with a left hand! What's keepin' these two guys up?
一个惊人的闭幕时刻!
A tremendous closing moment!
此刻巴尔博亚又起来了  拳王也是又打出一记左拳
Here comes Balboa back, but the champion back with another left!
《洛奇3》
他们是如何起来的我不知道
How did they getting out here, I don't know!
是一记右拳
A right hand!
是奎迪打的  现在换巴尔博亚了  现在又换成奎迪
It's Creed! Now it's Balboa! Now it's Creed!
洛奇打出了一记惊人的左拳
And now a tremendous left by Balboa!
他们面对面地站在擂台的中央
They're standing dead in the center of the ring, toe-to-toe!
一
One.
二
Two.
奎迪将能保住他的头衔  如果没人站起来的话
Creed will retain the title! If neither gets up
就是平手  奎迪就能保住头衔
it's a draw, and Creed will win the title!
四
Four.
- 老兄  起来吧  - 五
- Get up!  - Five.
六
Six.
两位选手都想打败读秒
Each trying to beat the count!
快起来
Get up!
- 八  - 他在发抖
- Eight.  - He's trembling!
九
Nine.
- 冠军倒下去了  - 十
- The champ is down!  - Ten.
你出局了
You're out!
他赢了
He won!
他在最后一秒时办到了
He's done it at the last second!
巴尔博亚站起来他办到了  洛奇巴尔博亚震惊了世界
Balboa got on his feet and he made it!  Rocky Balboa has shocked the world!
他是新任的世界重量级冠军
He is the new heavyweight champion of the world!
各位女士先生
Ladies and gentlemen,
在惊人的出乎意料中
in a stunning upset...
以一次击倒而赢得了胜利
scoring a win by a knockout...
新任世界重量级冠军
the new heavyweight champion of the world...
- 你很棒  - 洛奇巴尔博亚
- You were great.   - Rocky Balboa!
抱歉
Excuse me. Excuse me.
我只想告诉家里的妻子一件事
I just wanna say one thing to my wife, who's home.
艾莉  我办到了
Yo, Adrian! I did it!
我爱你  我爱你
I love you. I love you.
(世界冠军洛奇)
(洛奇赢得第一次头衔保卫战)
(洛奇巴尔博亚对抗裘萨克)
(洛奇巴尔博亚对抗美国重炮)
(洛奇击倒了德国冠军)
(洛奇已准备好第六次头衔保卫战)
(克劳伯廉第六度残忍地击倒对手)
(克劳伯廉现在排名第八)
放马过来  来啊  出拳打我
Come on, come on! Bring it to me!
再来  快
Come back! Come on!
这是提线木偶表演!
It's the Muppet Show!
今晚  洛奇巴尔博亚!
Tonight, Rocky Balboa!
我要巴尔博亚  我要巴尔博亚
I want Balboa!  I want Balboa!
听到没  老头子  叫洛奇敢就让他来找我
Hear that, old man? You tell Balboa to come here if he wants!
没有人能击败我  你告诉他我所说的
Nobody can beat me! You tell him what I said!
他就是下一个了  我要宰了他
And he's next! I'm gonna kill him!
告诉巴尔博亚  没有人能阻止我
Nobody can stop me! You tell Balboa that!
我会追着他的  你告诉他
I'm comin' after him! You tell him!
我想冲击拳王宝座
I want a shot at the title.
如果巴尔博亚玩这个游戏   他会在拳坛上或别处见到我
If Balboa's got the guts, he'll meet me in the ring or anywhere else.
我一生都在争取这头衔为目标
My whole life was directed towards this here title, and nothin'else.
我独自生活跟训练
I live alone and I train alone.
我会独自赢得头衔的  我吃定他了
I'll win the title alone. I want him.
他没法永远避开我  他避的了一时避不了一世
He can't duck me forever. He can run, but he can't hide.
又是一个左撇子
Well, another southpaw...
重量级拳王洛奇巴尔博亚  似乎不太担心
heavyweight champion Rocky Balboa, doesn't seem to be worried about much.
他刚卫冕了第十次
He's just defended his title for the tenth time.
而且已同意参加重量级摔角比赛
He's even agreed to take on the world's heavyweight wrestling champion...
目的是慈善义演
in a sort of charity benefit...
所得将捐给青年基金
with all the proceeds to go to a local youth foundation.
现在我必须称赞他
Now, I'll have to give him credit.
巴尔博亚先生设法使自己忙碌  他是个真正的运动员
Mr. Balboa manages to stay busy. He's a true sportsman.
他的头号对手克劳伯廉
And it looks like the number-one contender Clubber Lang...
将必须等待了
will have to continue to play the waiting game.
但那应该是一场伟大的比赛
But that should be a great, great matchup.
保利  放轻松点
Take it easy, okay?
你要走了吗?
Hey, you goin'?
别忘了向洛奇表达我的问候
Don't forget to give Rocky my best, huh?
你知道  我来这好几年了
You know, I've been comin' here years.
保利  你给我你的问候如何?
How about you give me, Paulie, your best once?
保利  轻松点
Take it easy, Paulie.
(胜利的季节)
保利  你听到了吗?
Paulie, you hear me?
当你见到洛奇时 告诉他我们都跟他问好
When you see the Rock, tell him the boys all say "hey"!
四万
Forty thousand!
我拿到了另一个
I got another one!
保利
Paulie.
你想听我欠你的吗?  我什么也没欠你
You wanna hear "I owe ya"?  You I owe nothin'.
你的确没欠我
No, you don't owe me nothin'.
那你希望我做什么?
So what do you want I should do?
- 我妹妹不在这吗?  - 她在家
- My sister ain't here?  - She's home.
你知道  我和她一直都很亲密  直到你出现
Well, me and her used to be tight until you come in.
我把她养大  她却不来探望我
I raised her, she don't come down.
她并不知道这些
She don't know about this.
知道吗  你跟她都可以下地狱了
You can up and go to hell, you know that?
保利  小心你的用词
Hey, watch your mouth, Paulie.
你想揍我吗?  我不会让你辛苦的
You gonna whack me? I don't sweat you.
我不会让你辛苦的  来吧
I don't sweat you. Come on.
保利  得了吧  为什么不把你的头脑弄清醒点
Come on, Paulie. Why don't you screw your head on right?
不  不是我的脑袋  是你畸形的脑袋出问题了
No, it ain't my head. Your freakin' head is the one on wrong.
是吗?
Yeah?
- 我做了什么?   - 你做了什么?
- Well, what did I do?  - What'd you do?
什么也没做  但你对自己可好了
Nothin'. For yourself?  Oh, nice.
你把自己打扮的很英俊  衣服很不错
You fixed your face up handsome, nice clothes.
你为保利做了什么?  有吗?
What'd you do for Paulie?  Anything?
三年了  你给了我工作吗?
Three years? Did you get me a job?
只有这个  你给了我一个差劲难看的手表  就这个
Just this. You gave me a lousy, stinkin' Ex-Lax watch. This!
- 保利  - 干嘛?
- Paulie  - What?  What?  There!
干嘛?  我说的没错  不  别捡它
That's right! No, leave it down!
反正它从来也没准过
It never kept good time anyway.
你忘了以前当那些人嘲笑你时
You forget when you were a punk and those guys used to laugh at ya...
因为你是那么可笑  是谁把那些无赖打走的?
because you were so jive. Who used to whack them bums out?
他们笑的是我们两个
They laughed at both of us.
没人嘲笑过我
No one laughed at me.
是谁帮你交上第一个女友的?
Tell me, who fixed ya up with your first woman?
是我  保利  是我负责的
Me, Paulie! I was responsible!
她当时怀孕了
She was pregnant.
那又怎样?  你也一样不名誉
So what? You was no prize either.
你知道的  我一直在帮你
You know, I always give ya. I give ya.
你呢?  你买了栋新房子
What do you do? You buy a new house.
还把米克接过来住  对吧?
You move Mick in, right?
你问过我吗?  有什么是想到我的?
Did you ask me? Is there somethin' the matter with me?
知道吗?  我是有感情的  不是厚纸板
I got feelin's, you know. This ain't cardboard.
保利  每个人都有感情的
Everybody's got 'em, Paulie.
去你的每个人
To hell with everybody.
不  也许该去的人是你
No, Maybe it's to hell with you.
我不想听这些废话
I don't wanna listen to this crap.
你认为大家都欠你一个生活
You talk like everybody owes you a livin'.
闭上你的嘴
Shut your mouth.
没有人亏欠你  是你亏欠你自己
Nobody owes nobody nothin'. You owe yourself.
你错了  朋友就亏欠我
You're wrong! Friends owe!
朋友并没亏欠你  他们做是因为他们想做
Friends don't owe! They do because they wanna do.
闭上你的嘴  你一直都在打压我
Shut your freakin' mouth. You been keepin' me down!
打压?
Down?
你对我而言就像个疯狂的兄弟  真的
You know, you're like a crazy brother to me.
你确实是  因此我告诉你一些事
You really are. So I'm gonna tell you somethin'.
这是我的肺腑之言  保利
This is comin' straight from the heart, Paulie,
而且我是认真的
and I mean this.
你并没被打压  也不是个输家
You ain't down, and you ain't a loser.
你只是个嫉妒
You're just a jealous...
懒惰的无赖
lazy bum.
够了  我要打烂你的嘴
Okay. I'm gonna break your mouth.
我要把你的嘴打烂
I'm gonna break your mouth!
我能有个工作吗?
Can I have a job?
你只要开口就有了
All you had to do was ask.
你的拳打得很好
You punch pretty good.
- 真的吗?   - 打得好极了
- Think so?   - Oh, superb.
- 这部车很贵吧?   - 对  有点
- Cost a lot, huh?   - Yeah, a few bucks.
你还有一部吗?
Got an extra one?
今晚和保利有什么麻烦吗?
Any trouble with Paulie tonight?
没什么特别的
No, nothin'unusual.
你真要跟摔角选手比赛?  他们都很高大的
Are you really gonna fight that wrestler?  They're so big.
没关系  会很有趣的
That's all right. It'll be fun.
介意我为你奏一首小夜曲吗?
You mind if I serenade you?
来吧  换你了
Come on. It's your part.
你在干嘛?
What are you doin'?
- 来吧  你做的到的  - 不
- Come on. You can do it.  - No.
洛奇  你会把宝宝吵醒的
Rocky, you're gonna wake the baby.
艾莉  快  我们来二重奏
Adrian, let's do a duet.
不  稍等片刻
No, hold on a minute.
很好  但不是"杜..."  是"嘟..."
That's good, but it's not "doe-doe's".
嘟...
doe-doe's, doe-doe's...
很好  亲爱的
That's good.
我曾被告知过
I've been told
嘟...
doe-doe's
人们和大家都
By people And they all,
嘟...
doe-doe's
说他们会接纳我
Said you'd take me back
像以前一样接纳我
Take me back like before
怎么了?
What's the matter?
其他的我不会唱了
I don't know any more of the composition.
也许我们是幸运的
Maybe we're lucky.
- 是  也许我们很幸运  - 非常幸运
- Yeah, we're very lucky.  - Very lucky.
你们好  运动迷们
Howdy, sports fans.
我是丹尼斯詹姆斯  正和吉姆希利在拳击场
This is Dennis James with Jim Healy down here at ringside.
今晚我们要为你报导一场最不可能的比赛
Tonight we have a most unlikely match for you
拳击手对抗摔角手
the boxer against the wrestler
所有收入将做慈善用途
with all the proceeds going to charity.
你觉得拳击手和摔角手在同一个擂台如何?
What are your feelings about a boxer against a wrestler in the same ring?
你知道有个古老的理论
Well, you know, the age-old theory is...
曾经摔角手抓到过拳击手  作者是这么写的
that the wrestler, once he grabs that boxer, that's all she wrote.
你的脑袋里到底在想什么?
What the hell goes on inside your head?
还有正常的功能吗?
Anything normal functions?
有  还有一点
Yeah, there's a few.
我可不认为  要和这种人打
I don't think so. Because to fight a creature like this...
会有一百磅的脑子受伤
you gotta have about 100 pounds of brain damage.
我看过比恐龙还大的摔角选手
I seen wrestlers that was bigger than dinosaurs.
你曾和恐龙打过吗  孩子?
You ever fight a dinosaur, kid?
- 没有  最近没  - 他们会造成各种伤害的
- No, not lately.  - They can cause a variety of damage.
世界摔角冠军正在进场
The wrestling champion of the world is now entering the arena...
他体型庞大全身通红
and he is quite a sight-all decked out in red.
他们为何抬着他?
Why are they carryin' him?
他正在散步
He's walkin'.
巴尔博亚  我来了
I'm comin' after you, Balboa.
把比赛取消吧
Let's call it off.
行了吧  这是为了慈善的
Come on. It's for charity.
你会为了慈善而肚破肠流的  没人会牺牲这么大的
You're wearin' your anatomy out for charity. Nobody else does this much for charity.
鲍伯霍伯就会
Bob Hope would.
那倒是
That's true.
洛奇  你最好打电话给鲍伯霍伯
Rocky, you better call Bob Hope.
我所有的爱奴们
To all my love slaves out there...
雷吻就在这里  全身都是肌肉  宝贝
Thunderlips is here, in the flesh, baby.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
终极的男人对抗
The ultimate male versus...
终极的饭桶
the ultimate meatball.
天啊  他真是个怪兽
Boy, he is a monster.
你要多少钱才肯跟他比赛?
How much would you take even to get in the ring with him?
从黄金储存处的那些钱开始吧
Would you like to start at Fort Knox?
在白色角落的是  令人难以置信的情景
In the white corner, an incredible sight...
身高将近七英尺
standing nearly seven feet...
重达390磅
weighing 390 pounds...
他真庞大  对吧?
the undisputed...
- 世界摔角冠军  - 这是世界上最粗的手臂
- wrestling champion of the world....  - That's the biggest arm in the world!
一个称他自己为"欲望的终极目标"
a man who calls himself the ultimate object of desire...
"熔化欲望的山脉"
the mountain of molten lust...
唯一的
the one, the only...
雷吻
Thunderlips!
你们都是垃圾
You're all trash!
另一位是来自费城的  职业拳击家
In the far corner, the slugger from Philadelphia...
你们最好闭嘴
You better shut up!
我要把他撕成两半
I'll break him in half!
你想他一餐吃多少?
How much do you think he eats?
大概202磅吧
About 202 pounds.
体重202磅
weighing 202 pounds...
首屈一指的世界重量级冠军
the reigning heavyweight champion of the world...
洛奇巴尔博亚
Rocky Balboa!
请到擂台中央来
Come to the center of the ring, please.
好  来吧  米克
Okay, come on, Mick.
好  两位  这只是好玩而已
All right, you guys, you know this is for fun...
所以放轻松  让他们看场好的表演
so take it easy and give 'em a good show.
听着  比赛后  我们一起拍张拍立得照片  好吗?
Listen, after the match, how about we get a Polaroid together, okay?
你有麻烦了
You're in trouble.
我要把他像这样撕成两半
I'm gonna break him in half like this!
最近好像每个人都想揍我
Seems like lately, everybody wants to beat me up.
- 这只是娱乐  - 我要揍扁巴尔博亚
- This is entertainment.  - I'll squash Balboa!
扮鬼脸  绕着擂台移动
Stay awake! Make faces! Move around the ring!
懂吗?  他就跟擂台一样大
Got it? He is the ring.
每次他那么做我都会很紧张
I get nervous every time he does that.
对一个大汉来说  你移动得很快  知道吗?
Whoa. You move pretty fast for a big guy, you know that?
我们何不四处移动一下  给观众看个好表演
Listen, why don't we just move around a little bit, like give 'em a good show.
我追你而你也追我
First I'll chase you, then you chase me, okay?
如何?  我会轻轻打的  我来了
How's that?  All right?  We'll go easy.
- 还好吧?  伤到了?  - 别靠近他!
- Is that okay?  Does that hurt?   - Stay away from him!
那样会痛  还好吧?
That hurt, all right?
如何  没事吧?  还不坏吧?
How's that?  Okay?  Not bad, huh?
快  饭桶  来吧
Come on, meatball! Come on!
这全是假的  饭桶  全是假的
Think it's all fake, meatball?  All fake?
雷吻已经彻底发狂了
Thunderlips has gone absolutely berserk.
快逃命吧
Run for your life!
到终点站了  饭桶
Last stop, meatball!
爬起来  小子  来吧  饭桶  做些正经事吧
Get up, boy! Come on, meatball! Get some of this right here!
洛奇  注意四周
Rocko, remember the neighborhood!
别走近他
Get out of his way!
不  还没呢  别替饭桶读秒
No, I'm not yet, not for the meatball.
我还没把他丢出去呢
I'm not done with him yet, boy.
如果我打不破你的意志  但我确定可以打破你的背
If I can't break your spirit, I sure enough can break your back!
爸爸觉得好玩吗?
Is Daddy havin' fun?
当然
Of course.
起来!
Get up!
谁给我把斧子!
Somebody lend me a hatchet!
我的天啊
Holy smoke!
来吧  宝贝  熄灯了  饭桶
Here we go, baby! Lights out, meatball!
我的天啊  巴尔博亚真的很痛苦
Oh, my God! Balboa is really in pain!
没人能相信这超人的力量
No one can believe the superhuman strength of Thunderlips!
我是雷吻  我才是男人
I am Thunderlips,  I am the man!
阻止他好吗?
Stop him, will ya?
你们要这个拳击沙袋吗?
You want this punching bag?
艾莉
Adrian?
洛奇
Rocky
抓住我
Catch me!
难以置信!
That's incredible!
巴尔博亚被抛到第五排去了
Balboa was just heaved clear into the fifth row!
现在观众也被激怒了
Now the fans are outraged too.
我要像拖块破布般把他拖下走道
I'm gonna drag him down the aisle like a dirty rag!
你这胆小鬼  巴尔博亚
You weakling, Balboa!
放轻松
Take it easy!
- 怎么了  米克?   - 是我的心脏
- Mickey, you okay?   - My heart.
保安正在试图冲进去阻止这场比赛
Now the security guards are rushing in, trying to stop this slaughter.
观众落荒而逃  牙齿也四处乱飞
Teeth are flying all around!
- 解开我的手套  - 你完了吗?
- Cut my gloves off!  - Why?  You finished?
快  解开我的手套
Come on! Cut my gloves off!
一个保安飞了出去  这真是个动物园
A security guard flying through the air! The place is a zoo!
这地方变成了动物园
This place has turned into a zoo! This is very, very
要我叫医生吗?  你确定?
Want me to get a doctor? You sure?
女孩们也牵扯进来了  她们正在痛打
The girls have gotten into it now. They're getting beat up.
你这个傻瓜要去哪里?
Where are you going, you fool?
- 我马上回来  - 你这个疯子  快回来
- I'll be right back.  - You're a maniac! Come back here!
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
快回来
Come back here!
来吧  你
Hey, come on!
- 蠕虫们  别挡路  我来了  - 过来
- Out of the way, worms!  - Come on!
来吧
Come on! Come on!
好了  雷吻  快放手  放手
All right, Thunderlips, break it up! Break it up!
不准勒他
No choking! No choking!
我不会让你辛苦的
I don't sweat you!
撑下去  孩子
Hang on! Hang on there, kid!
你觉得如何?
How do you like it, huh?
你还真可爱
You're kinda cute.
我不需要这个
I don't need this.
洛奇完全地勒住了他
Rocky is out-and-out strangling him.
洛奇就像牛头犬般地撑着  现在洛奇正在勒他的颈子
Rocky hanging on like a bull terrier. Now he's got him in a stranglehold.
攻击身体
The body!
把他的脑袋打掉
Knock his block off!
- 大树要倒了!  - 不!
- Timber!  - No!
这真是难以置信  洛奇真的做到了
It's unbelievable! Rocky actually did it!
那庞然大物被丢到擂台外去了
A human skyscraper's been thrown out of the ring!
好  就这样  时间到了
All right, that's it. Time is up.
各位女士先生  结果是平手
Ladies and gentlemen, we have a draw. A draw.
谢谢你们来参加  第12届年度慈善比赛
Thank you, one and all, for attending the 12th annual charity match
由意大利杜马洛奇巴尔博亚
between the Italian Stallion Rocky Balboa...
和终极男人雷吻演出
and Thunderlips, the ultimate male.
明年再见了  谢天谢地
See you next year. Thank God.
- 你还好吧?  - 是  很好
- Are you all right?  - Yeah, pretty good.
好比赛
Good match.
你在台上为什么对我那么狂暴?
Why'd you get so crazy on me out there?
那就是比赛的实质
That's the name of the game.
趁你还平静的时候  我们能一起拍张拍立得吗?
While you're still calm, can we get that Polaroid together?
当然  没问题
Yeah, sure.
艾莉  过来  这是我妻子艾莉  我小孩
Adrian, come on over here. My wife Adrian, my kid.
这是雷吻  你会拍照吗?
That's Thunderlips. Al, would you do that?
- 那样很痛  - 没关系的
- That hurt.  - Okay, that's all right.
你知道  有时慈善反倒是伤人的
You know, sometimes charity really hurts.
(洛奇和雷吻募集了 七万五千元)
小木偶说谎  所以他的鼻子开始变长
Pinocchio told a lie, and his nose started growin' real big.
为什么不是他的耳朵?
Why didn't his ears grow?
我不知道  我不是故事的作者
I don't know. I didn't write the story.
你又要打拳了吗?
Are you fighting again?
今天?  不  今天我不打算打拳
Today?  No, I don't plan on fightin' today.
- 你保证?  - 保证  绝对不打
- Promise?  - Promise. Definitely I promise.
好  我喜欢你在这里
Good. I like you here.
我也喜欢在这里  你饿了吗?
Yeah?  I like bein' here. Are you gettin' hungry, huh?
要麦片吗?
You want some Wheaties?
- 什么是麦片?   - 冠军
- What are Wheaties, huh?   - Champions.
- 什么的早餐?  冠军  - 冠军
- Breakfast of what?  Champions.  - Champions.
熊爸爸说 "有人在我床上睡觉"
And the father bear, he says, "Somebody's been sleepin'in my bed. "
而小熊也说 "有人在我床上睡觉"
And the little kid bear said "Somebody's been sleepin' in my bed,"
"她在那里"
"and there she is."
因此  它把被子掀开
Thereby he pulls back the covers...
使她显露在大家面前  懂吗?
and thereby exposing her to the, you know, public, see?
来  趁麦片还没沉淀把它吃掉吧
Come on, eat your cereal before it sinks.
然后那位金发美女怎么了?
Then what happened to Goldilocks?
她怎么了  我也不太确定
What happened to her?  I'm not exactly sure.
因非法侵入被抓  并关在牢里三十天
Busted for trespassin' and got 30 days in the clink.
保利  这样跟孩子说还真好
That's real nice, Paulie. That's nice to tell the kid.
洛奇  车子在等着呢
Rocky, the car is waiting.
你们最好快去吧
You guys better go.
- 你要乖乖的  - 我们在这会很有趣  我和孩子
- Be a good boy now.  - We'll have a fun time, me and the kid.
杜马太太  你看起来真漂亮
Oh, Mrs. Stallion, you almost look pretty good.
保利  谢谢
Oh, thank you, Paulie.
别让那孩子喝啤酒  好吗
Don't give the kid any beer, all right?
保利  我们得走了  别把他带到竞赛场上  好吗?
Okay, we gotta go. And Paulie, don't take him to the track, all right?
米克  你好吗?
How ya doin', Mick?
很好
Pretty good.
现在  我们在第七局遇到问题
Now, we got a problem in the seventh.
不管曾发生了什么  现在是宁静柔和的时刻  对吧?
Whatever happened to them quiet, tender moments, huh?
谢谢  谢谢大家
Thank you. Thank you, one and all.
偶而总有人会挑战可能性
Every once in a while, a person comes along who defies the odds...
挑战逻辑
who defies logic...
并实现一个不可思议的梦想
and fulfills an incredible dream.
我代表费城所有的市民
On behalf of all the citizens of Philadelphia...
和其他被你的成就所感动的人们
and the many who have been touched by your accomplishments...
及被你不知疲倦地参加本市许多慈善活动所感动的人们
and your untiring participation in this city's many charity functions...
我们很荣幸地  呈献这座纪念碑
it is with tremendous honor that we present this memorial...
它将会永远歌颂
which will stand always as a celebration...
人类不屈服的精神
to the indomitable spirit of man.
费城向他最喜爱的子民致敬 洛奇巴尔博亚
Philadelphia salutes its favorite son Rocky Balboa!
真是太美了
It's beautiful.
绝对是件杰作
Definitely a thing of beauty.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常感谢大家
Thank you very much.
我不知道  不知道你们面对这个会说什么
I don't know what, what do you say to something like this?
大约三年前
About three years ago...
这个城市
this city...
真的感动了我  你们知道吗?
really took me inside, you know?
而我想为此好好地感谢你们  真的
And I want to thank you very much for that. I really do.
我一直在想  我不打算提起这个的
And I've been thinkin' that I wasn't gonna bring this up,
但我现在可能要提了
but I might as well now.
我绝不会做任何事来伤害这运动
I would never do anything to to hurt this sport
它使我获益匪浅
that has been so really good to me.
我一直和我的妻子
And I've been talkin' it over with my wife...
及我的经纪人谈起
and my manager...
我们认为
and we think that
这真的很难启齿  我觉得好像
Well, it's really hard to I feel like, well
我在想也许是我该…
I'm thinkin' maybe it's time that I should...
下台退休的时候了
step down maybe and retire.
不  不
No! No!
趁还可以的时候退休吗?
Gettin' out while you can?
别给这蠢货雕像  给他胆子
Don't give this sucker no statue. Give him guts!
我说过我不会走的
I told you I wasn't goin' away.
你表现过了  现在换我表现了
You got your shot. Now give me mine.
快滚开
Get the hell outta here!
闭嘴  老头  我不会走的
Shut up, old man! I ain't goin' nowhere.
告诉这些好乡亲  你为何躲着我吧
Now why don't you tell all these nice folks why you been duckin' me?
是政治  老兄  这国家想打压我
Politics, man. This country wants to keep me down,
使每个人都软弱
keep everybody weak.
他们不要我赢得头衔  因为我不像他是个傀儡
They don't want me to have the title because I'm not a puppet like that fool.
知道吗?  你的嘴巴真大
You know, you've got a big mouth.
巴尔博亚  何不做个了断呢?  来吧
Why don't you come out and close it, Balboa?  Come on!
随时奉陪
Anytime.
他疯了  别听他胡说
The guy's crazy. Don't listen to him.
那个小人不来找我  那我就说出事实吧
The little man don't wanna come to me. I'll come to you and tell the truth.
我是第一流的  一流的
I am ranked number one. One!
那表示我是最优秀的
That means I'm the best.
这无赖却挑软柿子吃  跟其他的无赖比赛
But this bum is takin' the easy matches, fightin' other bums.
我告诉你和在场的所有人
I'm telling you and everybody here...
我将不收分文  不计时间地点地跟他比
I'll fight him anywhere, anytime, for nothin'.
但你们不会看到这场比赛的  因为他要退休了
But you people ain't never gonna see that happen because he's gonna retire.
他不会和真的男人打的
You see, he don't fight no real man.
- 他参加设计过的比赛  - 什么?
- He fight them setups.  - What?
你是这个运动中的耻辱
You're a disgrace to this sport!
闭嘴  老头  你不知道我经历过什么
Shut up, old man! You and that chump don't know where I had to come from.
巴尔博亚  你的家庭很美满  不是吗
Balboa, your family doin' real nice, ain't it?
你称自己是个斗士?  证明吧
You call yourself a fighter. Prove it now.
给我同等的机会
Give me the same chance.
你躲我的方式真是个耻辱
The way you been duckin' this is a disgrace.
如果他不是懦夫  为何不和我打呢?
If he ain't no coward, why don't he fight me then?
- 我听不下去了  - 我不管你是第几流的
- I can't listen to any more of this.  - I don't care what you're ranked.
你不会有比赛的  我是说真的
You don't get no shot, and I mean that!
很高兴你们都看到这一切了
I'm glad you're seein' this.
我想和他打
I wanna fight this guy.
好  你去和他打
Well, you've got him.
但我不会陪你的
But you fight him without me.
- 什么?  - 事情结束了
- What are you sayin'?   - It's finished.
对  我不做了  我不要再看到这一切了
Yes, I'm finished. I don't want no more of this.
我不要再看到这一切了  懂吗?  不要了
I don't want no more of it. You understand?  None of it!
- 全都结束了  - 用我比赛的记录评价我
- It's all over with!  - Judge me by my fightin' record.
女人  那个女人  听我说
Hey, woman. Hey, woman. Listen here.
既然你的丈夫没勇气  也许你想看看真正的男人
Since your man ain't got no heart, maybe you'd like to see a real man.
我敢说你每晚都睡不着  梦想能有个真正的男人
I bet you stay up late every night dreamin' you had a real man, don't you?
我告诉你
I'll tell you what.
今晚你到我公寓来  我给你看看真正的男人
Bring yourself over to my apartment tonight, and I'll show you a real man.
你想比  那就比吧
You want it, you got it!
随时奉陪
Anytime!
洛奇  不要
Rocky, don't. Come on.
洛奇  拜托  让我们谈谈
Rocky, please, let's go talk.
洛奇
Rocky
让我们谈谈
Rocky. Let's talk.
你为何离开?
Why'd you leave?
为何走得那么急?
Why'd you walk away like that?
生命太短暂了  孩子
Life's too short, kid.
你要去哪?
Where are you goin'?
我要去度个永远的假
I'm goin' on a permanent vacation.
你在说什么?  我们还有一场比赛
What are you talkin' about? We got one more fight.
不  不是我们  是你
No, not we. You.
你为何要这么做?
Why are you doin' this?
我说你为何要这么做?
I said, why are you doin' this?
因为你赢不了的  洛奇!
Because you can't win, Rock!
这家伙可以在三回合内把你打死
This guy'll kill you to death inside of three rounds!
你疯了
You're crazy.
讲点新鲜的吧
What else is new?
他只是另一个拳击手
He's just another fighter.
不  他不是另一个拳击手
No, he ain't just another fighter.
这家伙是个毁灭机器  而且他很有战意
This guy is a wreckin' machine, and he's hungry.
你从赢得冠军之后  就再没有战意了
Hell, you ain't been hungry since you won that belt.
你在说什么?  我已经卫冕十次了
What are you talkin' about?  I've had ten title defenses.
那是容易的
That was easy.
什么意思?
What do you mean, easy?
那些都是筛选过的
They was handpicked!
- 设计过的吗?  - 不  不是设计过的
- Setups?  - No, they weren't setups.
他们是很好的拳击手  但他们不像这家伙是个杀手
They was good fighters, but they wasn't killers like this guy.
洛奇  他可以把你轰到未来
He'll knock you into tomorrow, Rock.
天啊  米克
Geez, Mick.
你为何要这么做?
Why'd you do it?
因为阿波罗对你的攻击  原本会杀了你的
Because the beating that you got from Apollo should've killed you, kid.
但却没有  我的工作是让你一直赢
It didn't. It was my job to keep you winnin'...
并让你保持健康
and to keep you healthy.
你真的没有认为  我什么都不剩了  对吧?
You really don't think I got nothin' left, do you?
洛奇
Well, Rock,
让我们这么说吧
Well, let's put it this way.
三年前你是能人所不能
Now, three years ago, you was supernatural.
是坚毅而狂暴的
You was hard and you was nasty...
而且你有铸铁般的下颚
and you had this cast-iron jaw.
但最可怕的事发生在你身上了
But then the worst thing happened to you...
也可能发生在别人身上
that could happen to any fighter.
- 你变得文明了  - 对
- You got civilized.  - Yeah
别担心  孩子
Oh, don't worry, kid.
你知道的  总统会退休  将军也会退休  马匹
You know, presidents retire, generals retire, horses retire,
和战场上的人都会退休
Man O'War retired.
他们把它用来配种
They put him out to stud.
那才是你原本该做的  退休
That's what you should've done, retire.
米克  知道这些后我不能退休了
I can't retire knowin' all this, Mick.
- 别逼自己  - 你一直照顾着我
- Oh, don't push it.  - Well, you been carryin' me.
我们不需要打的
We don't need it.
你一直在照顾我
You've been carryin' me though.
我没有照顾你  我是在保护你
I haven't been carryin' ya. I been protectin' ya.
不  听着  我要打这一场  再一场就好了
No, it's not the way, I want this fight, just one more.
- 我们不需要打的  - 我会住到健身房去
- But we don't need it.  - I'll live in the gym.
- 我们不需要打的  - 米克  我要
- We don't need it.  - Mick, I do.
我求你再训练我最后一次
And I'm askin' you to train me one last time.
不  我不能
Oh, no, I can't.
如果你不能
If you don't...
我就告诉大家  你十年没买过一件新内衣
I'll tell everybody you ain't bought a new pair of underwear in ten years.
你会这么做的  对吧?
You would, wouldn't you?
对  没错
Yeah, absolutely.
不
No, no.
别这样
Come on.
再一次  然后就结束
One more time, then it's over.
成交了吗?  来吧
It's a deal?  Come on.
孩子  这可是你的生命
It's your head, kid. It's your head.
对  没错
Yeah, it is.
谢了  米克
Thanks, Mick.
(重量级冠军每天在这里训练)
(世界重量级冠军)
洛奇穿的袍子  刚刚送来的  快来买吧
Hot off the truck. Clean stuff. Get your robes.
(洛奇)
一生只有一次
Collectors' item! Once in a lifetime!
快来买装饰钮扣吧
Get your buttons here!
你不可以直接面对那家伙
You can't stand toe-to-toe with this guy.
否则他会把你丢到火星上
or he'll deposit you up there on Mars someplace.
他太厉害  太强了
He's too tough. He's too strong.
听着  我们怎能在这肉麻下流的地方训练呢?
Listen. Now how the hell can we train in this creep joint here?
我的意思是  这是一栋有坏名声的房子  不对吗?
I mean, this is kind of a house of ill repute or somethin', isn't it?
你为什么租这里呢?
Why did you rent this joint?
别这样  米克  让我们够派头点
Oh, come on, Mickey. Let's go out in style, okay?
要像样地出去  就得全身而退
You wanna go out in style, go out in one piece!
我们离开这里
Now let's get outta here.
回到旧健身房去吧
Let's get back to the old gym, will ya?
让我们流些血汗和泪吧
Let's get some blood and sweat and tears around here.
- 能做到吗?   - 请你放松并享受它  好吗?
- Can we do that?   - Just relax and enjoy it.
米克  他们很喜欢的
They love it, Mick.
来  加油  继续
Go fight! Fight now. Go ahead.
加油  强悍点
Fight it, fight it. Get rough, get tough.
狠一点  就是这样
Get brutal. That's it.
抱歉  我能亲你一下吗?
Excuse me. Could I get a kiss?
好  当然
Yeah, sure.
滚开好吗?
Get outta here, will ya?
这就像在动物园里打架一样  这是个动物园  你知道吗?
It's like fightin' in a zoo. It's a zoo, you know?
你是这样准备比赛的吗?
Is that the way you train for Clubber?
他不会亲你的  他会杀了你  你知道吗?
He ain't gonna kiss ya. He's gonna kill ya. You know that?
继续  快滚开
Get outta here!
洛奇  照张像如何?
Yo, Rock! How about a picture?
- 好  - 照好了
- Yeah, sure.  - There ya go.
速度再快一点
Put a little speed on there!
很好  就是这样
Put a little speed on there! That a boy.
好  这才像样
All right, this'll tell us the story.
快  一边一边来
Fast! Side to side.
一边一边来  洛奇
Side to side, Rock!
后面的闭嘴  好吗?  改变你的调子
Shut up back there, can't you?  Change your tune.
就是这样  出拳  出拳  出拳
That's it! Punch, punch, punch!
就是这样  孩子  你是个致命武器
That's it, kid. You're a deadly weapon.
时间到  住手
Time, time, time. Quit it.
表现不错  加油
You're okay. Come on.
- 在你得肺炎前先穿上它  - 好
- Put this on before you catch pneumonia.  - Okay.
- 我帮你按摩一下  - 好
- I'll give you a little rubdown too.  - Yeah.
听着  孩子
Hey, listen, kid.
我不喜欢听别人太多废话
I don't like to hear much of what comes out of people's mouths.
也不喜欢轻声细语的时刻
And I don't like soft-talkin' moments.
- 那是当然的  - 但我要告诉你一件事
- That's for sure.  - But I just wanted to tell you one thing.
我以你为荣
I'm proud of you.
- 谢了  - 不客气  孩子
- Well, thanks a lot.  - That's all right, kid.
- 我们离开这里吧  - 米克
-  Let's get outta here.  - Hey, Mick?
什么事?
Yeah?
- 等结束后我们该做什么?  - 不知道
- What'll we do when it's all over?  - I don't know.
也许参加马戏团或什么的
Maybe join up with a circus.
- 对  也许吧  - 好  我们出去吧
- Yeah, maybe.  - All right, let's go.
洛奇
Rocky
各位晚上好  我是比尔鲍德温
Good evening, everyone. Along with Bill Baldwin
晚安  我是赖士图
I'm Stu Nahan,
我们欢迎你们欣赏今晚的重量级卫冕赛
and we welcome you to tonight's heavyweight title fight...
这也许是最值得纪念的比赛
which may prove to be the most memorable of all.
因为今晚是卫冕者最后  也许是最艰难的卫冕赛
For tonight is the champion's final and perhaps most difficult title defense.
洛奇  你觉着现在是职业生涯的最佳状态吗
Rocky, do you feel you're in the best shape of your career?
没错  我感觉很好
Oh, yeah, absolutely. I feel real good.
他是个致命武器  他是那种人  他也会那么做的
He's a deadly weapon. He's one of a kind, and he's gonna do it.
克劳伯  你认为你和巴尔博亚一样快吗?
Clubber, do you think you're as fast as Balboa?
- 我不想说话  - 克劳伯  为我们跳舞吧
- I'll do my talkin' in the ring!  - Clubber, dance for us.
你最好滚开  我想独处
You better get outta here! I wanna be alone!
- 你在比赛后会退休吗?   - 会  这是最后一次
- Will you retire after this fight?   - This is the last one.
在这以后我和米克都结束了  这是最后一次
After this, me and Mick are finished. This is definitely the last one.
你们都是寄生虫和吸血鬼  滚开
Y'all parasites and leeches! Get outta here!
今晚之后你将会做什么?
What will you do after tonight?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
- 米克  也许加入马戏团是吗?   - 对  享点乐子
- Maybe join the circus, eh, Mick?  - Yeah. Have some fun.
快点  把袍子脱下吧
Come on, take your robe off!
我说过叫你们离开的
I told you to get outta my face!
今晚和我们一起的是前任重量级拳王  阿波罗奎迪
With us this evening is the former heavyweight champion Apollo Creed.
你对这场比赛有什么预测吗?  你怎么看今晚的比赛?
Do you have any predictions on this fight? How do you see this fight going tonight?
我觉得体力是挑战者较好
I feel its strength would have to go to the challenger...
但经验和世界上最硬的头  却是巴尔博亚的
while experience and the world's hardest head would have to go to Rocky Balboa.
你知道我了解的
I know about that.
洛奇  记住  别跟他讨价还价
Now remember, Rock. Don't trade with this guy.
把握时间  打击他
Take your time, wear him down...
但别直接面对他
but don't stand toe-to-toe with him.
这混球以前从未打到过15回合
This punk's never been 15 rounds before.
- 好好修理他  - 好
- Take him good.  - Okay.
- 好好修理他  - 我会的
- Take him good.  - Okay. I will.
就是这样
That's it.
我预测卫冕者会获胜
So I predict that the champ's gonna take it.
请等一下  你认为卫冕者真的有机会?
Now wait a minute. Do you really think the champion can hit that hard?
你认为我为何和你坐在这里到比赛结束?
Why do you think I'm sittin' out here with you?
蠢货巴尔博亚  你死了  你完了
Hey, sucker! Balboa, you bum! You finished!
你彻底完蛋了  废物  我是世上最坏的
You through! You washed up! I'm the baddest in the world!
- 对我你还没那么坏  - 纸老虎  你说什么?
- You're not so bad to me.  - What you say, paper champion?
我像打狗一样地打败你
I'm gonna beat you like a dog!
你们能把那猩猩赶回台上去吗?
Can't you get that ape back into the ring?
你害我等太久了  你得为此付出代价
You made me wait too long! You gonna pay!
来吧  大嘴巴
Come on, mouth!
把他赶出去好吗?  把他赶出去
Get him outta there, can't you?  Get him outta there!
让开  别挡着我
Let me go! Let me go! Get outta my way! Get outta my way!
你知道我是谁吗?  我是男人
You know who I am?  I'm the man!
你只是一堆死肉  我要在台上会你
You're nothin' but dead meat! I'll meet you in the ring, sucker!
你是一堆死肉
You're dead meat!
放开我
Let go!
洛奇
Rocky
- 怎么了?  - 他的心脏
- What's wrong?  - It's his heart.
艾莉  怎么回事?  快叫医生来
What's wrong, Adrian?  Get a doctor!
快叫医生来  快
Somebody get a doctor! Come on!
米克  坐在这里  把他们赶出去
Sit here, Mick. Get 'em outta here!
把他们赶出去
Get'em outta here!
- 请你坐在桌上好吗?   - 我没事
- Mick, will you sit on the table?   - I'm all right.
深呼吸  把这些家伙赶出去
Just take a deep breath. Get those guys outta here!
快  米克  你能坐吗?
Move! Mick, will you sit on the table?
保利  告诉他们比赛取消了  快去
Paulie, tell 'em the fight's off. Go on! Go on!
不  比赛不能取消  你是疯了吗?
The fight's not off. Are you outta your mind?
要继续  你疯了吗?
The fight's on. You crazy?
- 今晚不能继续  - 可以  今晚我们要比赛
- Mick, we can't, not tonight. I ain't fightin'.  - Yes, tonight we're gonna fight.
我不能喘口气吗?
Just let me get my breath.
这违反了规则或什么吗?
Can't I get my breath? Is that against the rules?
保利  你能叫医生来吗?
Would you please get a doctor, Paulie?
他正在路上
He's on his way.
米克  我不能像这样地出场比赛
Mick, I can't go out there and fight like this. I can't go out like this.
出场去吧  快去  好吗?
Now get out in there. Get goin', will ya?
快去修理他  好好修理他  把比赛完成  好吗?
Take him good. Get it over with, why don't ya?
艾莉  我该怎么办?
Adrian, what am I supposed to do?
你是什么鬼意思?  你不知道该怎么办?
What the hell do you mean, what are you supposed to do?
我们在一起这么多年了  你不知道该怎么办?
After all these years together, you don't know what to do?
你应该感到惭愧的
You oughta be ashamed of yourself.
现在快去把比赛完成吧
Now get out there and do it.
快去
Do it.
去吧
你是最强的
You're the best.
好吧
Okay.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
艾莉  好好照顾他
Adrian, take care of him. Take care of him.
晚安  各位女士先生
Well, good evening, ladies and gentlemen...
欢迎参加特别的
and welcome to the featured event...
世界重量级拳王卫冕赛
for the heavyweight championship of the world.
各位拳迷  今晚和我们一起的是拳坛上的伟人之一
And fans, with us tonight, truly one of the fistic greats...
他将从擂台旁上来  他就是灾难之王
he's coming up from ringside, the Master of Disaster,
刺痛之王
the King of Sting,
唯一的阿波罗奎迪
the one and only Apollo Creed!
他上台了  前世界重量级拳王阿波罗奎迪
And there he is, the former heavyweight champion of the world Apollo Creed.
他看起来气色很好的样子
Stu, he looks like nine million dollars.
滚出我视线  我不要你没有的东西
Get outta my face! I don't need nothin' you got no more!
我不需要过气的拳王在我这里
Don't need no has-been messin' in my corner.
在我揍你之前  快把你的丑脸移开吧
And you better get that bad look off your face before I knock it off.
来吧  你想打我吗?  打我吧
Come on. Wanna jump?  Jump. Come on.
来吧  奎迪
Come on, Creed.
来吧
Come on!
对  来吧
Yeah, come on!
对  你就像个胆小鬼  你最好快逃
Yeah, just like a chicken. You better run.
把这蠢货击败  当成给大家的礼物  好吗?
Give everybody a present and drop this chump, all right?
好  祝你幸运
All right. Good luck to you.
好  各位拳迷  我们开始了
All right, fans, here we go.
在我左边的是  由蓝色角落出现
On my left, in the blue corner...
由芝加哥呐喊过来
hailing from Chicago,
体重达235磅
weighing in at an even 235 pounds...
世界头号的挑战者  未被击败过的
the world's number-one challenger...
- 不知道米克怎么了  - 不可战胜的克劳伯廉
- I wonder how Mick's doin'.  - the undefeated Clubber Lang!
我是最强的  我是最强的
I'm the best. I'm the best!
你和克劳伯说过话  有何评论吗?
You and Clubber exchanged words up there. Any comment?
不予置评
I have no comment.
而在对角
And his opponent, in the opposite corner...
在全世界都不必介绍的
really needing no introduction to the world over.
他的体重刚好201磅
He weighs in at a trim 201 pounds.
费城的荣耀  意大利杜马
The pride of Philadelphia the Italian Stallion
首屈一指的世界重量级拳王
and the reigning heavyweight champion of the world...
洛奇巴尔博亚
Rocky Balboa!
听听观众的欢呼
Listen to this crowd.
这位是裁判马提邓肯
Now to give instructions in the middle of the ring...
the referee, Marty Denkins.
克劳伯  洛奇  你们知道规则的  我要一场干净的比赛
Clubber, Rocky, you know the rules. I want a good, clean fight.
我要你们照我的命令后退并分开
When I tell you to break, I want you to step back at my command and break.
回到角落去  等听到铃声再出来比赛
Now go back to the corner and come out fighting at the bell.
死人
Dead meat.
这不会是一场狡诈的比赛
This is not gonna be a fight of finesse.
这两位真的是拳击好手
These are two guys that really throw punches.
- 比赛结束时一定相当精彩  - 卫冕者害怕了
-  This could end with one punch.  - Chump's scared.
打垮他
Yeah. Hang him up.
你看到他的眼神了吗?
See the look in his eyes?
我不是教练  但出去把他杀了吧  洛奇  杀了他
Rocky, I'm no trainer. Just go out and kill the guy. Kill him, Rock.
他害怕了
He's scared.
我是新拳王  告诉你们  我是今天的新拳王
I'm the new champion, I tell ya. I'm the new champ as of today!
在多采多姿生涯中
The Italian Stallion, a rugged champion in the final
最后一场比赛的粗犷拳王
fight of his colorful career tonight.
吉米伦敦说的没错  他看起来很棒
Jimmy Lennon was correct. He looks like well, just great.
开始了  天啊  卫冕者跳跃着出场了
Here we go. Oh, boy! The champion came out swinging!
巴尔博亚有个令人意想不到的开始
Balboa's off to an incredible start.
他看来决心要除掉那位挑战者了
He looks determined to destroy the bigger challenger.
快进去  把他逼回去
Get in there! Move him back!
防守
Defense!
巴尔博亚又开始了  两人你来我往
Now it's Balboa! They're goin'at each other!
你逮住他了  洛奇  你逮住他了
You got him! You got him, Rock!
速度快点
Double up! Double up!
来吧
Come on!
挑战者用尽一切力量攻击卫冕者
The challenger is hitting him with everything he's got.
巴尔博亚  来吧  你让我等急了
Come on, Balboa! You made me wait!
巴尔博亚  来吧
Come on, Balboa!
克劳伯走开了 试着想回到他的角落去
He hobbles away to his corner.
保利  抓住他
Grab him, Paulie.
- 米克在哪里?  - 他没事
- Where's Mick?  Where's Mick?  - He's okay.
我现在需要他  我需要他
I need him here. I need him.
他没什么了不起  我告诉你们他没什么了不起
He ain't nothin'! I told you he ain't nothin'!
- 他太强了  - 洛奇  别这么说
- He's too strong.  - Don't talk like that. Come on.
- 把他撕成粉碎  - 我会打败他的
- Tear him up!  - I'm gonna smoke him.
我没有办法甩开他  我没有办法甩开他
I can't keep him off. I can't keep him off.
他是我的了  我会逮住他的
He's mine! He's mine! I'm gonna get him!
保利  我要输了  米克在哪里?
I'm losin' it, Paulie. Where's Mick?
- 血压多少?   - 200/50
- What do you got there?   - 200 over 50.
好  开始心肺复苏术
All right, let's start CPR.
- 洛奇  你办得到的  - 我会试试看
- Come on. You can do it.  - I'll try.
第二回合  洛奇显然是步履蹒跚
Round two. Rocky appears to be staggering.
对  我会逮住他的
I'll get him.
克劳伯正由角落出来
Coming out of the corner, here comes Clubber!
我会做给你看
I'm gonna show you!
来吧  巴尔博亚  打我
Come on, Balboa! Hit me!
打我吧
Give it to me!
看看你能不能打过来  打过来吧
Let's see what you can do!
在内圈移动
Move on the inside!
卫冕者相当的无助  天啊  他的拳威力真大
The champion is helpless. What a beating he's taking!
- 这不是真的  左拳  - 别直接面对他
- Unreal! A left to the  - Don't stand toe-to-toe with him!
巴尔博亚  来吧
Come on, Balboa
- 爬起来  - 无赖  爬起来
- Get up.  - Get up, Italian!
- 无赖  爬起来  - 五、六
- Come on! Get up!  - Five. Six.
七、八
Seven. Eight.
九、十
Nine. Ten.
你输了
You're out!
真不可思议
Unbelievable! Incredible! What an upset.
角落里的巴尔博亚倒在地上
Balboa in the corner out on his feet.
我们有结果了
We have the time.
以击倒而获胜的
The winner by knockout
新任世界重量级拳王
new heavyweight champion of the world
克劳伯廉
Clubber Lang!
对  我说过我会做到的
I told you I'd do it!
对  我是新任的世界冠军
Yeah! I'm the new champ of the world!
来吧  离开这里
Go on! Get outta here now!
- 洛奇  怎么回事?   - 米克怎么了?
- What happened?   - I'm all right. How's Mick?
- 他不肯去医院  - 什么
- He wouldn't go to the hospital.  - What?
这很重要  我们必须马上把他送去医院
Time is important. We must get him to the hospital immediately.
好
Okay.
米克?
Mick?
- 干嘛?  - 米克
- What?  - Mick
干嘛?
Wha...What?
结束了吗?
Is it over?
对  结束了
Yeah, it's all over.
听着  怎么回事?
Hey, what happened?
他击倒我了
It was a knockout.
- 哪一回合?  - 第二回合
- What round?  - Second round.
对  我就知道  很好
That'll do it. That's good.
我们做到了  不是吗?
We did it, huh?
我们做到了
We did it. We did it.
- 你不必再担心了  - 对  很好
- You don't have to worry anymore.  - Yeah, okay.
米克  一切都会没事的
Everything's going to be okay.
- 知道吗?  - 我知道我们做到了
- You know?  - We did it.
你必须到医院去  你已不像以前那么年轻了
We gotta get you to a hospital. Get how you used to be again.
你知道
You know,
我们把每件事都做对了
we did everything right.
不  听着  我们没把每件事都做对
No. No, listen to me. I did everything right.
听着  我们还有更多事要做
We ain't done everything right. We got more to do.
米克  不管你要做什么  我们一起做  好吗?
Whatever you want to do, we'll do it. Okay?
孩子  我爱你
I love you, kid. I love you.
你的本能
Your instinct
米克?
Mick?
米克
不要  上帝
It isn't...Jesus Christ!
别离开  求求你
Don't go away. Please don't.
我们还有更多事要做
We got things we didn't do.
我们还有更多事要做  我们要
We got more to do. We got...
我的天啊
My God
天啊
Jesus
仪式结束了
This concludes our service.
(纪念敬爱的米克高密尔  1905年4月7日-1981年8月15日)
(米克  伟大的拳击)
那不是正确的方法
That's not the way to do it.
谁?
Who's that?
你为何不直接打击他?  直接靠近他
You should hit it straight. Step into it.
阿波罗?
Apollo?
没错  我在你家等了一小时
Right. I waited at your house for about an hour.
你太太说你可能在这里
Your wife said you might be here.
你来这干嘛?
What are you doing here?
来办正事
Business.
如果报社知道我们这样谈话  他们会以为我们疯了
If the papers knew we were talking like this, they'd think we was crazy.
你为何这样?
Why you?
因为我是最好的  而你需要人来教你一些不同的
'Cause I'm the best, and you need somebody to teach you different.
为什么?
Why?
我不认为没有我的话  你能挽回颓势
To be honest, I don't think you can pull it off without me, Rock.
你还是没回答我  阿波罗
You still didn't give me the answer. Apollo
真正的原因是什么?
What's the real reason?
听着  现在很宁静不是吗?
Listen. It's quiet, isn't it?
当你退休  一切都太宁静了
When you retire it's too quiet.
总之我们都太年轻了  不能退休
We're too young to retire anyway.
此外  用正确的方法
Besides, with the right touch...
我可以把这件事  推进有史以来最伟大境界
I could promote this thing into the gate of all time.
比我们想像的还大
It'd be bigger than ours.
天知道  我不介意名利双收
Heaven knows, I don't mind being involved with large numbers.
对吧?
Right?
我再也不要了  我
I don't need this no more. I...
我再也不要了
I don't want this no more.
听着  兄弟
Look, man.
当你打败我时  我伤心的要命
When you beat me, I hurt all over.
我不想知道任何人的事  甚至是我孩子的事
I didn't want to know from nobody, not even my kids.
每个拳击手都知道失败很伤人
Every fighter knows that hurt.
我们试着要和受伤的内心共存  所以现在别退缩
We get sick inside trying to live with it. Don't back off now.
为了自己  你得把它做对  否则你会遗憾的
Make it right for yourself or you'll be sorry you didn't.
我们都曾有过世上最伟大的头衔  宝贝
We held the greatest title in the whole world, babe.
你输了那场比赛  只为了错误的原因
You lost that fight for all the wrong reasons.
你失去了你的优势
You lost your edge.
好  我知道你的经纪人死了
All right, I know your manager dying.
使你内心一团糟
had you all messed up inside.
但事实是你没有战意
But the truth is, you didn't look hungry.
当我们比赛时
When we fought
你有老虎般的眼神  那就是优势
you had that eye of the tiger, man the edge.
你得把它找回来  把它找回来的方法就是从头开始
Now you gotta get it back and the way to get it back is to go back to the beginning.
你知道我的意思吗?
You know what I mean?
也许我们可以一起把它赢回来
Maybe we could win it back together.
老虎般的眼神  男人
Eye of the tiger, man.
你为什么要来呢?
Why'd you have to come here?
我有计划  卷土重来  男人
I have the plan. Get back, man.
你使我好奇了
You got me curious.
洛奇  你也使我好奇了
You got me curious, Rock.
克劳伯  你接受跟巴尔博亚的重赛吗?
Clubber, do you accept the challenge for a rematch with Balboa?
我拒绝挑战  因为巴尔博亚根本不是个挑战
I reject the challenge, because Balboa is no challenge.
但我很乐意再多揍他一些
But I'll be more than happy to beat up on him some more.
我总是说他什么也不是
I always said he was nothin'.
我等不及要看那蠢蛋失败了
I can't wait to see him fall.
你认为  他被阿波罗训练的事如何?
What do you think of him being trained by Apollo Creed?
阿波罗是谁?
Apollo who?
是那个老傻子阿波罗奎迪吗?
You talkin'about that old fool Apollo Creed?
- 过气的人教另一个过气的人  - 对  继续说吧  老兄
- One has-been teaching another.  - Just keep talking, pal.
我见到他时会让他闭嘴
When I see him, I'm gonna close it.
好  比赛何时举行?
All right. When will the match take place?
越快越好  我是世界冠军
The sooner the better. I'm the champion of the world.
这是无庸置疑的  我不能被打败  也不会被打败
Ain't nothin'can be done about that. I can't be beat and I won't be beat.
这次我要练得更认真
This time I'm gonna train even harder.
我不会很快击倒他  我要折磨他
There won't be no quick knockdowns. I'm gonna torture him.
我要好好地虐待他
I'm gonna crucify him real bad.
这是硬汉说的硬话
Hard words from a hard man.
巴尔博亚想在三十四岁  东山再起的胜算是很渺茫的
The odds against Balboa making a comeback at 34 are very long indeed.
他做的到吗?  大部分专家都怀疑
Can he do it?  Most experts doubt it.
巴尔博亚曾是很好的冠军  但他的时代已过去了
Balboa was a fine champion, but his time has passed.
我祝他好运
I wish him luck.
洛奇  别听他的
Don't listen to it, Rocky.
不  听他的  洛奇
No, do listen to it, Rock.
比赛结束后  许多民众将欠你一个郑重的道歉
When this is over, a lot of folks are gonna owe you an engraved apology.
而你也将欠我一个大人情
And you're gonna owe me a big favor.
什么人情?
What favor?
等比赛结束后吧
When it's over.
洛奇  来吧  我们快来不及去机场了
Rocko, come on. We're gonna be late at the airport.
- 我们走吧  - 你想我们忘了带什么吗?
- Let's go.  - Have you forgot anything?
- 我想我们都带了  - 也许再带一件毛衣
- I think we have it all.  - Maybe another sweater.
不  加州可没那么冷
Nah, California's not that cold.
好极了  上车吧
It's great. It's scorching.
听着  我要你乖乖的  好吗?
Listen, I want you to be a good boy, okay?
- 好的  - 别让任何人头痛
- Okay.  - And don't give anybody a hard time.
亲我一下
Give me a kiss.
- 下飞机后我们会打电话回来  - 对  我们会的
- We'll call when we land.  - Yeah, we'll call.
你会听话吗?  好了
You'll be a good boy?  All right.
我会带东西回来的
I'll bring you back something.
我们在洛杉矶要做什么?
What the hell are we doin' here in L.A.?
- 老兄  这是我开始的地方  - 那么
- This is where I started.  - So?
也是他开始的地方
So this is where he's startin'.
这个地方让人厌恶  我们为何不留在你那儿?
This place is disgusting. Why don't we stay at your place?
你错过重点了
I think you're missing the point.
我们先登记再到体育馆去
Let's check in and get over to the gym.
我认为我们不需要这地方
Rock, in my opinion, we don't need this place.
这里不符合你的标准
This is below you and the sister's standard.
我们得试试看  来吧
We gotta give it a try. Come on.
我连把枪都没有
I don't even have a gun.
有趣是有趣  我喜欢这类东西  但我不喜欢这个
Now, fun is fun. I like those kinds of things. But this I don't like.
你看这地方  老鼠甚至都不想待在这里
Look at this place. Rats even have more pride than to be caught dead here.
我是说  你看那些垃圾  我不喜欢
I mean, look at the dump. I just don't like it.
- 为艾莉的健康着想吧  - 保利  我很好
- Think of Adrian's health.  - I'm fine, Paulie.
是巴尔博亚  他来这干嘛?
It's Balboa, what's he doing here?
这是我发迹的地方
This is where I started.
那是你的问题  我们在他们打死我们之前离开吧
That's your problem. Let's leave before they leave us for dead.
你看到他们的眼神了吗?
You see that look in their eyes?
当我们比赛时  我练得很辛苦  但我眼中没有那种眼神
When we fought I trained hard, but I didn't have that look in my eyes.
你有  所以你赢了
You had it, and you won.
你得把那种眼神找回来
You gotta get that look back.
兄弟  老虎般的眼神
Eye of the tiger, man. Come on.
来  我们走吧
Let's go.
你看这地方  一点水准也没有
Look at this place. No class in here.
- 他一直都这么令人愉快吗?  - 我可没累着你
- Is he always so cheerful?  - I don't sweat you.
别心理不平衡了
Don't get mentally irregular.
这是个自由的国家
It's a free country.
别不平衡了
Just don't get irregular.
我不需要什么哲学课程
I don't need no philosophy lesson here.
我花了六年时间才了解他
It just takes about six years to get to know him.
我可没六年的时间
I ain't got six years!
保利  别这样  放轻松
Come on, Paulie. Just relax.
我们做正事呢
We're on business.
冠军
Hey, champ!
杜克  我的兄弟
Hey, my man!
什么都准备好了
Everything's set up and ready to go, baby.
我知道你认识他的
I know you know who this man is.
和你一起工作会很愉快的  而非对立
It's gonna be good working with you. Certainly had enough of working against you.
- 你觉得如何?  - 很好
- How do you feel?  - Pretty good, thanks.
我们一直活得很现代  但训练要用旧方法
We've been living modern, but now we're gonna train old.
我要和这些人谈谈
I'm going over here and talk to some of the guys.
冠军回来了
The champ is home!
我们得离开了  我的名声可是很好的
We've gotta leave. I've got a reputation.
什么意思  名声?
What do you mean, reputation?
你听到了  我不喜欢他们
You heard. I don't like these people.
你不喜欢他们?
You don't like them?
好吧  也许他们也不喜欢你
Well, maybe they don't like you either.
我对他们做什么了?
What did I do to them?
他们叫我重拳王
And they call me punchy.
杜马  来这里见见一些人
Stallion, come on over here and meet some of the fellas.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
各位  你们好吗?
How you doin', guys?
就是这样  快  用脚尖跳
That's it. Come on. On the toes,
用脚尖跳
on the toes.
快点  洛奇
Come on, Rocky.
他的动作不怎么优雅
He ain't too graceful.
所以我们才要来
That's why we're here.
浪费时间  他的脚很重的
You're wasting time. He's got heavy feet.
用脚跳吧  洛奇  来吧  放松些
Get on the balls of your feet. Come on. Relax.
把脚离开水泥地
Get those feet out of the concrete.
那得花些时间  但那会成功的
It'll take time, but it'll come.
他不能依着破丛林音乐来练
He can't train to the jungle junk music.
- 洛奇  来吧  放松些  - 开始了
- Relax, Rock.  - Here we go.
协调好双脚
Balance your feet.
- 让你的身体察觉到韵律  - 我们刚发明一种新舞叫爬行舞
- Let your body find the rhythm.  - Start a new dance called "the crawl."
我告诉你  你不能把他当成一个有色拳手来训练
You can't train him like a colored fighter.
他抓不到韵律感的
He ain't got no rhythm.
- 我看起来很蠢吧?   - 你看起来很好
- How stupid do I look?   - You look great
我们做的每一件事  都是为了练习刺拳
Everything we do works off the jab.
他会游泳吗?
Can he swim?
你是指洛奇吗?
With a name like Rock?
没时间浪费了  快练习吧  再一圈
No time to waste. Let's go. Another lap. Move it!
快游  再一圈
Another lap!
他可不是鲔鱼  我们是属于体育馆的
He ain't no tuna. We belong back in the gym.
他得利用一些  他不曾以为自己有的肌肉
He's gotta strengthen and use muscles he never thought he had.
来吧  伸展开来  洛奇  快游
Stretch, now. Move it, Rock!
没人可以改变那么多的  他是沙包  不是拳击手
Nobody could change that much. He's a bruiser. He ain't no boxer.
继续这么说  他会变得一无是处
You keep telling him that and he'll be nothing.
- 是吗?  - 再一圈  来吧  快游
- Yeah?  - Another lap! Come on, now!
快  快游
Move it! Move it!
来吧  洛奇  快游
Move it, Rock! Come on! Let's go!
就这样了  伸展  伸展开
That's it, stretch it. Stretch it out.
就是这样  快游吧  你得用力拉  加油
Let's go. You gotta pull hard, now.
闭嘴  你这无赖  我要揍扁你
Shut up, you Sterno bums! I'll squash ya!
有体面的人正想睡觉呢
There's decent people trying to sleep!
闭嘴  你这低级混蛋的人渣
Shut up, you honky scum bastard!
谁需要这恶心的地方?
Who needs this sick place?
我可不要
I don't.
没水准
No class.
该死  那个克劳伯很强壮
Damn, that Clubber's strong.
15回合是很长的时间
Fifteen rounds is a long time.
我们得趁早把他摆平
We gotta put him away early.
我认为步伐必须调整  洛奇还可以维持
I figure with the pace we gotta set, Rock can last maybe...
也许七或八回合
seven or eight rounds.
再过去我们就没辄了  兄弟
Then we'll be out of steam, man.
我们得趁早摆平他
We got to put him away early.
至少水还是热的
At least the water's hot.
我们从未度过真正的蜜月
Well, we never really had a honeymoon.
也没那么糟
It's not so bad.
我们一直处于恶劣环境中
You've been in worse places.
洛奇在第二回合有了麻烦
Rocky's in trouble in round two!
右勾拳  又一记右勾拳  洛奇遭到痛击
He takes a right and then an upper! He's been cut! Rocky's been cut!
快动吧  你得更厉害些
Come on, now.
流畅的思考  流畅些
You gotta get tougher. Think smooth.
脚趾  用脚趾跳
Bounce, bounce, bounce. Toes, toes. On your toes
洛奇  逼迫自己  集中注意
Push yourself! Concentrate!
洛奇  快移动吧
Let's move it! Move it now!
洛奇  来吧
Come on, Rocky, come on
放松  放松
Have fun with this. Have fun with it.
流畅点  用脚趾跳
That's it. Easy, easy.
别逼它  让它自然出现
Don't push it. Let it come.
宝贝  它会出现的  只是得花些时间
It'll come. It just takes time, baby.
来吧  移动你的头  把你的头上下移动
Come on, Move your head. Up and down.
流畅点  上下滑动
Come on. Slip now, up and down.
宝贝  进去
In and out. Inside. Inside, baby.
从一边到另一边
Side to side. Move your head.
注意  记住  他有两只手  好吗?
Watch him, now. Remember, he's got two hands, right?
该死  你究竟在干嘛?
Damn, man! What the hell you doing?
那家伙会打烂你屁股的
This guy will knock you on your ass!
洛奇  来吧  这不是游戏
Come on. It's not a game.
这次你想在医院躺五个星期吗?
You wanna live in the hospital for five weeks this time?
你以为我这样就很厉害了吗?  他会杀了你的
You thought I was tough?  This chump will kill you!
- 好的  - 把脑袋装到肩膀上去好吗?
- All right.  - Get your head on your shoulders.
想想那场比赛  想想那场比赛
Think about the fight. Think about the fight.
克劳伯廉他想伤害你
Clubber Lang's in, and he's trying to hurt you.
好  他来了
Here it comes.
他正在刺拳  他正想伤害你
He's jabbing. He's trying to hurt you.
你得打赢他  你得移动
You gotta fight him. Move!
他逮到你了  他逮到你了
He's hooking. He's hooking.
混蛋  洛奇  得了吧
Damn, Rock, come on!
你是怎么了?
What's the matter with you?
明天  我们明天再练
Tomorrow. Let's do it tomorrow.
已经没有明天了
There is no tomorrow!
没有明天了
听着  你只要记住一件事  我们得快些
Look, there's just one thing that you gotta remember. We gotta get some speed.
你得有弹性些  你得快速移动  知道吗?
You gotta get some flexibility. You gotta get some quickness. You understand?
- 快速  忍耐  - 这就是结尾
- Quickness and endurance.  - That's the end of it.
那就是我们唯一关心的事
That's the only thing we gotta concern ourselves with.
米克从不叫我这么做
Mickey never had me do this.
好了  我们开始了
Okay, here we go.
好了吗?
Ready?
- 准备  - 好  - 开始
- Set?  - Yeah  - Go!
跑
Come on!
快啊
洛奇  你赢不了的
You can't win, Rock!
你自从得那奖牌后  就失去战意了
You ain't been hungry since you won that belt.
他会把你轰到未来去
He'll knock you into tomorrow.
怎么回事?
What's the matter?
完了
It's over.
全完了
It's all over.
你究竟是怎么了?
What's the matter with you?
我能和你谈谈吗?
Can I talk to you?
我要问你一些重要的事  我也想要你告诉我事实
I wanna ask you something important and I want you to tell me the truth.
干嘛?
What?
你为什么来这里?
Why did you come here?
我再也不要了
I just don't want it no more.
如果它的结束是你要它结束的话  我很高兴
If it's over because you want it to be over, I'm glad.
我是要结束它
I do.
这是  从我认识你以来  你从未放弃过什么
It's just you've never quit anything since I've known you.
我不知道你要我说些什么
I don't know what you want me to say.
我是说如何?  怎么了?
I mean, what happened?
为什么以往都是那么好的东西  如今都变的那么坏?
How did everything that was so good get so bad?
什么事坏了  告诉我  什么?
What's so bad?  Tell me, what?
因为我为自己着想  而坏了一切事情
I wrecked everything by not thinking for myself.
为什么米克不告诉我怎么开始是正确的
Why couldn't Mickey tell me where it was right from the start?
他没有必要带领我  对我撒谎  使我以为
He didn't have to carry me and lie to me and make me think...
- 自己比真实的还要好  - 他没有撒谎
- I was better than I really was when I wasn't.  - He never lied.
那些比赛是不对的  艾莉  它们不对
Those fights weren't right. They weren't.
我从未和处在巅峰的人打过
I never fought anybody who was all in their prime.
我一直有个看法  那就是我能保有更久的头衔
It was always some angle to hold the title longer than I should've had it.
你了解我在说什么吗?
Do you understand what I'm saying here?
我知道  但你必须知道
I understand, but you've gotta understand
爱你和保护你是他的工作
that he loved you and that was his job-protecting you.
但保护一点用也没有  只会使事情更糟
But that protecting don't help nothin'. It only makes things worse.
过去几年我一直以为我是胜利者  但如今醒来发现自己是个失败者…
You wake up after a few years thinking you're a winner, but you're not.
但事实上是个失败者  所以我们不能保有头衔那么久
You're really a loser. We wouldn't have had the title as long.
但至少那也会是真的
So what?  At least it would've been real.
那是真的
It was real!
什么都不是真实的  如果你都不相信自己的话
Nothing is real if you don't believe in who you are!
我再也不信任自己了  你不明白吗
I don't believe in myself no more! Don't you understand?
当一个拳击手不相信自己时  他就完了  结束了
When a fighter don't believe, that's it! He's finished! It's over!
- 当然不是这个样子  - 当然是这样
- That's not it!  - That it is.
为什么不告诉我实话
Why don't you tell me the truth?
你把我当成什么了?
What are you putting me through?
你想知道事实?  事实是我不想失去我已有的
You wanna know the truth? The truth is I don't wanna lose what I got.
一开始我不在乎会发生什么
In the beginning, I didn't care about what happened to me.
我会到擂台上  开始出拳  但现在有你  有孩子
I'd get busted up. I didn't care. But now there's you, the kid.
- 我不想失去我所拥有的  - 我们有什么不能取代的东西吗?
- I don't wanna lose what I got!  - What do we have that can't be replaced?
房子吗?  我们有车子  有钱
A house. We got cars, money.
我们什么都有了就是事实
We got everything but the truth.
该死  事实是什么?
What's the truth, damn it?
我害怕  可以吗?  你要听我说出来吗?
I'm afraid, all right? You wanna hear me say it?
好  我害怕  这是我一生中第一次害怕
You wanna break me down? For the first time in my life, I'm afraid!
我也害怕  但害怕并不算什么
I'm afraid too. There's nothing wrong with being afraid.
- 对我而言当然是一回事  - 为什么?  你是人吧?
- For me there is!  - You're human, aren't you?
我只知道我是个骗子  只因为
I don't know what I am. All I know is I'm a liar and because of
米克不会再出现了
that Mickey ain't here no more.
你什么也没逼他做
You didn't push him into anything!
他是个成年人了  他必须做他必须做的事
He was a grown man and he did what he had to!
你没有权利为已发生的事内疚  没有必要
And you have no right to feel guilty for what happened.
你是个冠军  你做别人期望你去做的事
You were a champion and you did what you were expected to do...
你做我和其他任何人  认为你该做的事
and you did what I and everybody else thought you should do.
你要告诉我那些比赛都不是真的  我不相信
And you wanna tell me those fights weren't real? I don't believe it!
但我相信这不重要
But it doesn't matter what I believe...
因为你是那个内心恐惧的人
because you're the one that's gotta carry that fear around inside you...
害怕每个人都要带走你的东西
afraid that everybody's gonna take things away...
害怕会被人认为是个懦夫  再也不是个男人
afraid you're gonna be remembered as a coward that you're not a man anymore.
这一切都不是真的  我告诉你也没关系
Well, none of it's true. But it doesn't matter if I tell you.
因为你是要解决那事情的人
It doesn't matter because you're the one that's gotta settle it.
快扫除这魔障吧
Get rid of it,
因为当这烟雾被清除后  大家都称赞你的名字时
because when all the smoke has cleared and everyone's through chanting your name
将会是我们  你不能这样活下去  我们不能这样生活下去
it's just gonna be us! You can't live like this. We can't live like this.
因为那将会困扰你的余生
'Cause it's gonna bother you for the rest of your life.
看看那现在对你的影响是怎样
Look what it's doing to you now.
阿波罗认为你做的到  我也是
Apollo thinks you can do it. So do I.
你得为了正当理由去做
But you've got to want to do it for the right reasons
而不是为了对米克的罪恶感  不是为了人们  不是为了头衔
not for the guilt over Mickey, not for the people not for the title,
不是为了钱或是我  而是为你自己
not for money or me. For you.
只是你  只是你而已
Just you. Just you alone.
如果我输了呢?
And if I lose?
那么你就输了  但至少你输的没借口
Then you lose. But at least you lose with no excuses,
没有恐惧
no fear.
我知道你这样可以活的心安理得
And I know you can live with that.
你怎么变的那么坚强?
How'd you get so tough?
因为我和战士在一起
I live with a fighter.
我真的爱你
I really love you.
我爱你
I love you.
轻轻打
Just flick it.
好  再五圈
Five more laps.
打出去  逮住他
You gotta move in faster.
快  继续努力
Faster! Faster!
很好
Very nice.
移动头部  移动头部
Move your head! Move your head!
那样很好
That was nice.
来吧  来
Come on, come on
速度
Speed
预备
Ready
像鱼的洛奇
Rocky is fish
女士先生们晚安  我史都纳罕和比尔鲍德温一起
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. I'm Stu Nahan along with Bill Baldwin.
欢迎你们来到麦迪逊花园广场
We welcome you to Madison Square Garden
一场最激烈的拳击重赛
a most-exciting backdrop for the anxiously awaited rematch
前任冠军洛奇巴尔博亚
between the former champion, Rocky Balboa
挑战现今世界重量级拳王  克劳伯廉
and the reigning heavyweight champion, Clubber Lang.
现在镜头转至化妆间去
We now switch to our remote cameras inside the dressing rooms.
你能透露要如何攻击巴尔博亚吗?  你的策略为何?
Would you care to comment on how you plan to fight Balboa? What's your strategy?
什么也不需要
Don't need any.
巴尔博亚易于预测而且又笨  那家伙脑袋空空的
Balboa's so predictable and stupid. The man comes straight ahead.
对我而言他是订做的  而他将要受伤
He's tailor-made for me, and he's gonna get hurt.
很好  把那个倒过来
Nice, just make sure you turn them over.
那看起来如何  还好吗?
How does that look? Okay?
不  我不恨巴尔博亚  但我曾玩过那傻子
No, I don't hate Balboa, but I pity the fool.
我要摧毁任何一个想夺走我的头衔的人
And I will destroy any man who tries to take what I got.
记住你是从哪里来的
Remember where you came from.
记住你到这儿用了多少努力
Remember what it took to get you here.
记住他上次待你的方式  好吗?
And you remember what he did to you last time, right?
既然两个都是拳击手  优势是属于克劳伯
Since both men are brawlers, with the edge and power going to Lang.
我认为巴尔博亚想重赢头衔  十分困难
I would say that the odds are long against Balboa regaining his title.
现在该你了
Now it's your turn.
该你了  对吧?
It's your turn, huh?
- 你对比赛的预测如何?  - 预测?
- What's your prediction for the fight then?  - Prediction?
对  预测
Yes, prediction.
痛苦
Pain.
廉是个喜欢伤人的拳击手
Lang is a brawler who likes to hurt a man to the body.
你知道  从克劳伯廉残酷的痛击中
And Balboa may never have psychologically recovered
巴尔博亚永远不会回复过来
from that vicious knockout that Clubber laid on him.
(教练室)
时间到了
It's time.
- 拿去  - 干嘛?
- Here.  - What?
我要你把这穿上
I want you to wear these.
阿波罗  别这样  这是
Come on, Apollo. These are...
这是你我第一次比赛时你穿的
the colors that you wore in our first fight together.
- 我不能穿你的衣服  - 穿上吧
- I can't wear your colors.  - Just wear 'em.
阿波罗  谢谢
Apollo, Thanks.
在还我之前要洗好  可以吗?
Just make sure you wash 'em before you bring 'em back, all right?
我会的
Will do. Will do.
谢谢你  阿波罗
Thanks, Apollo.
记住  之后你就欠我一份人情了
And remember. After this, you owe me a favor.
什么人情?
What favor?
我同意  直接面对面的话
I have to agree. Toe-to-toe...
廉颇具毁灭性  而且他也太强了
Lang is utterly devastating and he's much too strong.
好的  听着  我只想说我以你为荣
All right, listen. I just wanna tell you I'm proud of you.
一个人要改变必须花大把劲  但你却做到了
It takes a hell of a man to change, and you did it.
- 你今晚就要证明它  好吗  - 好的
- You're gonna prove it tonight, right?  - Right.
- 阿波罗  做的好  - 保利  谢谢
- You did good, Apollo. - Thanks, Paulie.
- 保利  我们开始吧  - 我们走
- Let's do it, Paulie.  - Let's go.
洛奇来了  而阿波罗也来了  这两位前任拳王
Here comes Rocky and Apollo, the two former champions.
你看洛奇
Take a look at Rocky.
看他的脸  紧绷的身体
Look at the tenseness in his face, the tautness of that body.
- 他看起来可真严肃  - 没错
- Boy, does he look serious right now.  - He certainly does.
你知道  这是洛奇最后一战了  不管输赢或是平分秋色
And you know, the word is this is Rocky's last fight win, lose or draw.
他上台了  意大利杜马洛奇巴尔博亚  他正走上擂台
And there he is. The Italian Stallion Rocky Balboa, climbing into the ring.
他看起来可真瘦  对吧?
Boy, he looks incredibly thin, doesn't he?
我猜他一定瘦了20磅
I'd say he's gotta be about 20 pounds lighter.
洛奇巴尔博亚  费城来的铁人
Rocky Balboa, the iron man from Philadelphia.
今晚观众一定站在他那边  你听
And this crowd is certainly with him tonight. Listen
巴尔博亚其实并没有什么拳击技巧
Balboa doesn't really have any boxing skills.
我从未见过一个拳击手  有这么强的决心
I've never seen a fighter with as much raw determination.
等等  史都  看看我们的后面
Hold it, Stu. Here comes the champion now.
是克劳伯廉  听听这些观众
Clubber Lang. Listen to this crowd.
看看他们的眼睛  我从未见过这么阴沉的眼睛
Take a look at those eyes. I've never seen a guy with such sullen eyes.
他很强悍
He is tough.
克劳伯  回到你的地方去
Clubber, go back where you came from!
他进场时甚至殴打了一位观众  你看到了吗
He even belted a spectator on the way in. Did you see that?
- 你看看那个人  - 天啊  真是可怕
- Look at that man.  - Boy, awesome. Awesome.
可怕  他很强悍  你看那里
He's tough. Look at that.
克劳伯廉  世界重量级冠军
The heavyweight champion of the world.
- 只要快速  - 你  蠢蛋
- Just keep it as quick  - Hey, fool!
你准备好再挨打了吗?
You ready for another beating?
你不该再回来的
You should've never came back.
别看他
Don't look at him.
让我们冷静些
Let's just be cool.
小子
Hey, boy.
Boy.
我修理他后  你就是下一个
After I crucify him, you're next.
别让我看见你  傻子
Just stay out of my face, chump.
别背对着我  小人
Don't turn your back on me, sucker!
铃响前就开始打斗了
We got a brawl before the bell!
阿波罗和克劳伯廉要吵架了
Apollo and Clubber wanna go at each other right now.
铃声就要响了  比赛就要正式开始了
This thing is ready to explode! The fight is about to begin,
但这些家伙现在就想开始
but these guys wanna start right now!
- 别这样  - 放开我
- Come on  - Let me go, let me go.
我要逮住你  放开他
I'm gonna get you! Let him go!
来吧
Come on!
放开他  我要他
Let him go! I want him!
- 我想你说过要冷静  - 那就是冷静
- I thought you said, "Be cool."  - That was cool!
我是冠军   我会像上次一样揍你
I'm the champ! I'll beat ya like I did last time!
你不必找我了  我在这里
You won't have to look to find me! I'm here!
各位女士先生  及世界上的拳击迷们
Ladies and gentlemen, and boxing fans on the round of world
欢迎光临麦迪逊广场花园
Welcome to Madison Square Gardens...
观赏今晚的世界重量级冠军赛
and tonight's heavyweight championship of the world!
观众们都准备好了
This crowd is ready tonight.
在那红色角落
In the red corner
挑战者
the challenger...
重191磅
weighing 191 pounds.
从费城来的
From the fighting city of Philadelphia...
前世界重量级拳王
the former heavyweight champion of the world...
意大利杜马
the Italian Stallion...
洛奇巴尔博亚
Rocky Balboa!
我想说  他变得好瘦了
I'll tell you something. He has so slimmed down...
看起来像是中量级
he looks like a middleweight.
在蓝色角落里
Out of the blue corner...
重237磅
weighing 237 pounds...
出拳猛烈  来自芝加哥的
the hard-punching battler from Chicago...
现任世界重量级拳王
the reigning heavyweight champion of the world...
克劳伯廉
Clubber Lang!
裁判路菲利普
Referee Lou Filippo.
好  两位  我们开始吧
Okay, boy, let's go
我们讨论过规则了
We went over the rules yesterday.
我在此重复几点
I'm just gonna repeat a few of them.
当心腰部以下和对准后颈的攻击
Let's watch your low blows and the rabbit punches.
万一有人被击倒  你们就到角落去
In case of a knockdown, you go to the corner I tell you to
并待在那里直到我要你们出来
and you stay there until I tell you to come out.
懂吗?  有问题吗?
Is that understood? Any questions?
好的  现在回到各人的角落去  让我们开始
Okay, let's go back to your corner now. Let's go
我要打烂你
I'm gonna bust you up.
尽管来
Go for it.
开始了  战争开始了
Well, here we go. The war is on.
我们在等待着铃声
We're just waiting for the bell.
帮我拿冠军带  我要逮住那蠢蛋
Take my belt off. I'm gonna beat that chump.
别让这无赖使你依他的方式打斗  你是最强的
Don't let this bum let you fight his fight. You're the best!
去吧  冠军
Here you go, champ.
节奏和力量
Rhythm and power.
- 保持那个刺拳  - 谢谢
- Keep that jab up.  - Thanks.
准备看第一回合了吗?  一定很精彩
We're ready for round one now. Should be a great fight.
比赛开始了
And here we go.
他直接离开他的角落
Rocky goes right out of his corner!
他在紧逼克劳伯廉
He goes right after Clubber Lang!
移动正确并且左拳击中廉的脸部
He's throwing rights and lefts into Clubber's face.
真是个猛烈的开始
What a start of a fight here!
又一个刺拳
Another jab. Another jab.
还是刺拳  这可不是印象中的洛奇
And another. This is not the Rocky we expected.
他像阿波罗那样跳跃移动
He's dancing like Apollo Creed.
他看起来美妙极了
Looks fantastic.
又一记右拳
Another right.
是一记右拳  你看他左右摆动的头
There's a right. Look at that right to left to the head!
廉搞不清楚发生了什么事
Clubber Lang doesn't know what's happening right now.
他被这种方式刺伤了  你看他打的好拳
He's being stunned by this style. Look at the shots he's taking.
我真不敢相信  但他压制不了洛奇
I can't believe I'm saying this, but he can't corner the challenger.
那双脚滑溜溜的挑战者  真不可思议
It's absolutely unbelievable.
你只能打这么用力吗?  来打我吧
Come on! Bring it to me! Hit me!
那右手就像是支轻快的铁锤
That right hand is just like a trip hammer.
- 洛奇  缠住他  - 出拳打我吧
- Rocky, tie him up!  - Come on!
打我吧  退回去  来吧
Hit me! Step back! Come on!
真是棘手的第一回合…
Tough first round! Tough first round!
洛奇对廉打出几套组合拳
And it's Rocky with a couple of rights and lefts to Lang.
退下
Get off!
现在廉要卷土重来了
This crowd's going absolutely wild!
群众正在变得兴奋
The folks are becoming absolutely wired
那是洛奇左右拳的组合
There's a good left-right combination by Rocky.
一记好的左拳
And a good left hand!
今晚是属于洛奇巴尔博亚的
This is Rocky Balboa's night.
第一回合结束时  我们见到一场混战
We've got pandemonium in the ring at the end of round one.
廉还要再打  他不了解这一回合已经结束了
Lang wants more. He can't realize the round is over.
他试着回到洛奇身旁
He's trying to get back to Rocky.
好  你看起来很好
All right, all right. You look great.
别疯了  我们在休息区了
Just don't get crazy and we're home.
老兄  我要宰了你
I'll kill you, man!
那家伙很强壮
The man is strong.
我要在下回合杀了他  我要杀了他
Next round, I'm gonna kill him! I'm gonna kill him!
现在他陷入困境了  对吧
Now, he's gonna come hard, right?
你要一直缠着他  别让他有机会喘息
Keep crowding him. Don't give him a chance to set.
数节奏并移动
Counter and move. Counter and move.
我不认为廉知道第一回合 是什么东西打了他
I don't think Lang knew what hit him in this whole first round.
又开始了  第二回合铃响了
Here we go.
现在廉走出来要找洛奇  但现在洛奇在他的角落里
Now it's Lang coming out strong at the start of round two.
他又走回来了  但洛奇仍挥动着左右拳
Rocky's still landing those rights and lefts.
他现在在台中央使用右拳
He's using his right in the center of the ring.
一个接一个的右拳  他真的是在摆布他  右拳
He's really setting him up. Right, right, right!
五记没有还手的好拳
Five unanswered shots.
杀了他
Kill him!
离开那里
Get out of there!
回到这来
Get back there!
好了
All right!
放开他  快  分开
Come on! Break it up!
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
来吧  巴尔博亚
Come on, Balboa!
我要好好地揍你
Let's get those feet moving!
把手举起来  快  洛奇
Get your hands up!
那记右拳又击中洛奇
That right hand hurt Rocky again.
廉把他逼到角落去了  巴尔博亚有些小麻烦了
He's got him in the corner. Balboa's in a little trouble now.
该死  抓住他
Hold him, damn it!
洛奇  快
Come on, Rocky!
到目前为止这回合属于克劳伯  他有了动力
This is Clubber's round so far. Lang is taking the momentum here.
他逼住了巴尔博亚
He hold Balboa
- 巴尔博亚倒了  - 你最好站起来
- And Balboa is down!  - You'd better get up
站起来  该死
Get up! Damn it!
来吧  五
Five.
他站得起来吗?  他有麻烦了
Can he get up?  He's in trouble.
但他站起来了
He's up!
而克劳伯又来了  带了记左拳
And here comes Clubber again. Lang with the left hand.
又一记左拳  现在是右拳
Lang with another left hand. Now a right.
右拳  又一记右拳
Another right! Another right!
巴尔博亚又倒地了
And down goes Balboa again!
停止比赛
Stop the fight!
六
Six.
我有些招式
I got some more for you.
我还有许多招式  来吧
I got a lot of moves. Come on. Here we go again.
克劳伯走向他
Clubber coming into him.
你没那么差的
You ain't so bad!
- 你没那么差的  - 你一定是疯了或什么的
- You ain't so bad!  - You must be crazy or something!
- 我疯了?   - 你只是个蠢蛋
- I'm crazy?  - You're just a stupid fool!
- 但我可没喘得那么厉害  - 他是个傻瓜  笨蛋
- But I ain't breathing heavy!  - He is a fool!
遭受那样的重击他怎么恢复过来的
How could he come back from a beating like that?
你究竟在干嘛?
What the hell are you doing?
听着  那是战术  我知道我在干嘛
It's a strategy, that's all. I know what I'm doing.
不  你不知道你在做什么
You don't know what you're doing!
他会袭击你的  你是冠军
He's gotta come to you! You're the champ!
他什么也不是  他是我的
He's nothing! He's mine!
你直接面对这无赖的话  他会杀了你的
You stand toe-to-toe with this bum and he'll kill you.
别让自己的头被打掉
It doesn't take a man to stand there and get your head beat off.
- 别让...  - 他已经累了
- Don't...  - He's getting tired.
别浪费你的拳头  你是冠军了
Look, don't go wasting your punches! You're the champ!
别想一拳击垮他  用用脑子
Don't try to take him out with one punch! Use your head!
把他累垮  他是我们的了
Now, you wear him down, he's all ours.
我知道我在干嘛  我发誓
I know what I'm doing. I swear.
别告诉我你的想法
Don't tell me what you think!
到那里去完成它  老虎般的眼神  懂了吗?
Go out there and do it. Eye of the tiger. You understand?
好的
Yeah
出去把他的头打掉  他只是个人
Go out there and knock his head off. He's just a man.
要比他更像个男人  老虎般的眼神
Be more man than him! Eye of the tiger!
老虎般的眼神
Eye of the tiger!
从上到下  从左到右
Up to down, side to side
现在是第三回合  艰难的一回合
The beginning of round three. Tough rounds to call right now.
一开始有一些缓慢
This is a little slower than the start.
这回合是我的
It's my round.
- 这回合是我的  我这次会击垮你的  - 来吧
- It's my round. I'm gonna take you this time.  - Come on.
我要打败你  你是我的
I'm gonna take you. You're mine. You're mine.
- 来吧  - 我要打垮你
- Come on.  - I'm gonna get you.
离开那里
Get out there
刺他
Stick him!
- 他要被宰了  - 他不是要被宰了  他是快疯了
- He's getting killed!  - He's not getting killed. He's getting mad.
全世界都在看着  来  把我击垮吧
The whole world's watching. Knock me out!
来  用力地打我吧  快
You can hit hard! Hit me harder!
离开那里
Get out of there!
我妈打的都比那还用力  再用力点  打脸上吧
My mother hits harder than that! A little harder! Hit me in the face!
再来吧  快  你还不赖
Again! Come on! You ain't so bad!
我可能了解战术了  他要使克劳伯廉错过机会
I might believe the strategy now. He's making Clubber Lang miss now.
你看他如何引诱他了吗?  看看洛奇出的拳
See how he drew him in?  Now Rocky's throwing the punches. But look at the punches.
他正用打在肋骨上的拳  把他轰到台下去
He's lifting him off the canvas with those punches to the ribs!
就是现在
Now!
来吧
Come on
这地方已一片混乱了
The place has gone berserk!
真是了不起的东山再起
What a tremendous comeback!
站起来
Get up!
五、六、七
Five. Six. Seven.
八、九
Eight. Nine.
十  你出局了
Ten. You're out!
又是新的世界重量级拳王了
The new heavyweight champion of the world
他在那里
And there he is
新的世界重量级拳王  洛奇巴尔博亚
The new heavyweight champion of the world, Rocky Balboa!
洛奇精疲力竭了
Rocky is exhausted!
我们做到了
We do it.
各位女士先生  以击倒而获胜的冠军
Ladies and gentlemen, the winner by knockout
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
不会再好了
Never better.
再次地  世界重量级冠军
The heavyweight champion of the world...
意大利杜马
the Italian Stallion
洛奇巴尔博亚
Rocky Balboa!
快  我们有过协议的
Come on. We made a deal.
我知道  但这是很疯狂的
I know, but this is extremely crazy.
- 是心理不平衡  对吧?   - 没错
- It's mentally irregular, right?  - Yeah.
心理能使一切事情合理  你欠我一个人情
But it makes all the sense in the world. You owe me a favor.
我知道  但你什么时候想到这主意的?
I know. When did you think of this?
大约三年前
About three years ago.
- 真是太疯狂了  阿波罗  - 杜马  你看
- This is very crazy, Apollo.  - Look, Stallion
当你上次赢的时候  你一秒就赢了
when you won that last fight, you won by one second.
一秒钟就打败我了
You beat me by one second.
这对我很难接受
That's very hard for a man of my intelligence to handle.
但你不是说  你已学会如何和它共存了吗?
Didn't you say after I beat you, you learned how to live with it?
- 我骗你的  - 你骗我
- I lied.  - Oh, you lied.
所以你现在得向自己证明  对吧?
So now you just gotta prove it to yourself, huh?
只为了我自己  没有电视  报纸  只有你跟我
No TV, no newspapers. Just you and me.
什么都没有  只有你跟我  人得敬老尊贤的
Nothing. Just you and me. Age before beauty.
- 随你怎么说  杜马  - 我会尽全力的
- Anything you say, Stallion.  - I'll do all the work.
阿波罗  你最好慢一点
I'll tell you, you better go slow...
因为你已不再年轻了
'cause you ain't as young as springtime anymore.
我还年轻得足以揍扁你
I'm still young enough to whip your butt, Stallion.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
你是怎么做到呢?  你把你所知的都教我了
How are you gonna do that?  You taught me everything you know.
几乎一切都教我了  你得记住
Almost everything. You gotta remember, now.
你打得很好  但我是更伟大的拳击手  准备好了吗?
You fight great, but I'm a great fighter. You ready?
当然
Absolutely.
好了
All right
你知道  杜马  人变老真的是太糟了  对吧?
You know, Stallion? It's too bad we gotta get old, huh?
阿波罗  继续打吧
Just keep punching.
你要敲钟吗?
You wanna ring the bell?
好
All right. Ding, ding.
来吧
Come on
来吧  来
Come on, come on
天啊  对老人来说  你移动得很快了
Boy, you really move good for an older guy.
你看起来很好  我把你教的很好
You're looking good, Stallion. I taught you well.
我认为你把我教的太好了
I think you taught me too good.
- 你可以飞的  - 小心
- You can fly.  - Look out, now.
你不想要这个的  来吧
You don't want any of this. Come on.
- 来吧  - 也许我是和错的人在这里吧
- Come on.  - Maybe I'm in here with the wrong guy.
- 来吧  小心自己  - 准备好了?
- Watch yourself.  - Ready?
[谨以此片永远怀念珍·奥莉佛]